# **Kevin Hayes Anderson**

Chennai, India | kevinhayesanderson@gmail.com | +91 9585652041 | kevinhayesanderson.github.io

## **Employment Profile:**

Senior software and cloud engineer with 7 years of experience in Agile enterprise software development, cloud architecture, and development in multiple languages and microservices. Proficient in functional, low-level programming and Microsoft Azure Cloud Services. Interested in working with microservices using Rust.

## **Work History:**

Ambigai Consultancy Services India Private Limited, Chennai, India

Dec 2019 - Present

**Role: Software Development Lead** 

**Client: Schaeffler** 

- Developing pre- and post-processors Windows applications for finite element analysis software.
- Building core libraries for calculations in the cloud.
- Build a Native hosting suite to invoke core libraries in a native process from scratch.
- Improved performance in Web services, windows apps and in cloud calculation libraries.

Client: Goldbeck GmbH

• Developing Plugins for the Tekla Structures application.

Tech Stack: Functional Programming, Azure Functions, Azure Service Bus, Azure Storage & Azure DevOps.

#### Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai, India

Jan 2017 - Dec 2019

Project: Cigna HealthCare Role: .NET Developer

- Migrated legacy VB.NET application to ASP.NET MVC application.
- Developed and maintained backend services.
- Improved performance of batch processing background service.

Project: H&M

**Role: Full Stack Developer** 

- Developed Web APIs for domain services to support microservice architecture.
- Built a test automation suite using Selenium from scratch.
- Developed and maintained web applications built using the ASP.NET MVC framework and Angular.

**Tech Stack:** Angular, .NET Core, ASP.NET, Microservices, CQRS and RabbitMQ.

#### **Education:**

Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering, 8.1/10, Sastra University, Thanjavur, India

2012 - 2016

XII, 93.41/100, RSK HR. SEC. School, Tiruchirappalli, India

2010 - 2011

### **Skills:**

Front-end	Back-end	Windows	Languages	Others
Angular v16	.NET Core,	WPF,	C#, F#, Rust, JavaScript,	Selenium, Git, SQL
	ASP.NET	WinForms	Typescript, Python	Server

## **Certifications:**

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate, Acquired in October 2023. Credential link.

Cloud Developer using Microsoft Azure, Acquired in July 2023. Credential link.

**IBM Full Stack Cloud Developer,** Acquired in March 2022. Credential link.

Microsoft Technology Associate for Software Development Fundamentals, December 2016. <u>link</u>. Code: nSE6-XVNa And more...